<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Bai Hei</title>
    <link>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Bai Hei</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://heibaibai.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA molecular simulation</title>
      <link>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/dnamd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/dnamd/</guid>
      <description>The whole project is aimed to find the mechanism of DNA recognition and catalysis for HHaI, a DNA methylase. I am one of the team members to simulate DNA base-flipping using Amber 14 with an enhanced sampling method, SITS. This project gave me another perspective on researching biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA sequence information</title>
      <link>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/dna/</guid>
      <description>I began to produce data for this project from January 2017. We calculated the long-range correlation of DNA sequences of different creatures, and we analyzed the relationship of correlation length and gradient, chromosome structure and biological properties like longevity, evolution stage and incubation temperature.
This project is supported by Beijing Training Program of Innovation and Entrepreneurship for Undergraduates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza</title>
      <link>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/influenza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heibaibai.github.io/project/influenza/</guid>
      <description>During summer 2018, I worked with Prof. Michael W. Deem on prediction of vaccine efficacy as a visiting undergraduate researcher at Rice University, Houston, TX.
We combined pEpitope theory with generalized NK model in different ways and developed a method to predict vaccine efficacy of H3N2 just from sequence information and statistical mechanical model with high accuracy. It is a pretty good prediction with an r-squared equals to 0.91.
I presented a poster about this project in the 4th Annual Smalley-Curl Institute(SCI) Summer Research Colloquium and a paper for it is in progress to illustrate the results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>